http://www.fritzhansen.com/en-us/customer-service/privacy-policy

The basket will be cleared if the country is changed. Do you still want to change country?
PERSONAL DATA POLICY
This privacy policy is applicable to fritzhansen.com, owned by Fritz Hansen A/S, Allerødvej 8, 3450 Allerød, CVR no.: 14 12 02 11, Phone: + 45 4817 2300, E-mail: salessupport@fritzhansen.com
Fritz Hansen is subject to the personal data legislation in force from time to time, and any processing of personal information takes place in compliance with the Danish Act on the Processing of Personal Data. Pursuant to the Act on the Processing of Personal Data, Fritz Hansen should be regarded as the data controller responsible for the person information recorded about customers and visitors to the website.
Fritz Hansen collects information about you in a variety of ways linked to your use of its website. This policy describes the type of personal information we collect, how we process it and who to contact if you have any questions or comments about our guidelines. We guarantee fair and transparent data processing.
When we ask you to provide us with your personal information, we will inform you as to which information we are processing about you and for what purpose. You will receive details of this at the time your personal information is collected.
PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
The information we collect and use includes:
- Contact details, including name, e-mail address, address and phone number
- Information about interests and habits
- Purchasing history
- Transaction data
- Traffic data about use of the Internet
Your personal information will be collected in one or more of the instances below:
- When you complete a purchase in our online shop
- When you register to receive our newsletter
- When you set up a user account at My Republic/My Fritz Hansen
- When you take part in competitions
- When you communicate with us
We collect and store your personal information for the following non-personal and business purposes:
- Processing your purchase and providing our service
- Managing customer affairs
- Despatching newsletters or other marketing material, and other marketing initiatives
- Creating and managing your user account at My Republic/My Fritz Hansen
- Replying to your enquiries
- Statistics and analysis
The legitimate basis for our processing of your personal information is primarily to honour agreements concluded between you and Fritz Hansen. In addition, we process your personal information on the basis of your consent, for example when setting up a user account at My Republic/My Fritz Hansen.
Finally, we process your personal information on the basis of our legitimate interest in developing existing and new services and products, performing analyses and statistics of our customer segments, products and services.
We would point out that your personal information will only be used to send out marketing material if you have expressly given your prior consent.
We only process relevant personal information
We only process information about you that is relevant and adequate for the purposes defined above. The type of information about you that is relevant for us is determined by the purpose. The same applies to the scope of the personal information we use. We will not use more information, for example, than we need for the particular purpose in question.
We only process necessary personal information
We collect, process and store only such personal information as is necessary to achieve our stipulated purposes. Furthermore, the type of information needing to be collected and stored in order to run our business may have been stipulated in law. The type and scope of personal information we process can also be necessary in order to honour a contract or some other legal obligation.
We check and update your personal information
We check that the personal information we process about you is not incorrect or misleading. We also make sure we update your personal information on a regular basis.
Since our service depends on your particulars being correct and up to date, please advise us of any relevant changes to your details. You can use the contact information above to notify us of your changes.
We will delete your personal information when no longer needed
We delete your personal information when it is no longer needed for the purpose that provided our reason for collecting, processing and storing your data. However, such information can be processed and stored for longer in depersonalised form. Personal information collected in conjunction with completing a purchase on our website is kept with information about the goods you have bought for five years from the end of the financial year to which such information relates, cf. Section 10 of the Danish Bookkeeping Act, after which time the information is deleted.
Revocation of consent/Withdrawal
You can revoke any consents you may have granted at any time, e.g. in relation to newsletters, and close your user account at My Republic/My Fritz Hansen. We will then delete your personal information unless we can continue processing it on a different basis. If you wish to revoke your consent or close your user account at My Republic/My Fritz Hansen, you can contact us on salessupport@fritzhansen.com or +45 4817 2300, or use the cancellation link in the correspondence you receive from us.
Who we share personal information with
Our website is hosted by external suppliers COHESIO located in EU, who process the information on our behalf and as instructed by us. A copy can be required by contacting Fritz Hansen A/S.
The information can also be entrusted to and processed by our business partners in connection with the administration of customer affairs and marketing, as well as transport operators for use in delivering goods. In addition, your personal information will be passed on to the payment service provider AltaPay whenever you complete a purchase in the fritzhansen.com online shop. AltaPay is obliged to meet the requirements governing payment acquirers from time to time, including security requirements. AltaPay is also responsible for ensuring that measures to keep credit card numbers and pincodes safe are handled in line with the requirements set out in accordance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS).
Moreover, under certain circumstances and in accordance with legislation, it may be necessary to disclose information to public authorities, including judicial authorities. For instance, information can be passed on to the police in the event of suspected fraud etc.
SECURITY
We protect your personal information and have in-house rules regarding information security
We have adopted in-house rules regarding information security, which contain instructions and measures to protect your personal information from being destroyed, lost or altered, and from unauthorized publication as well as unauthorized parties gaining access to or knowledge of it.
USE OF COOKIES
Cookies, purpose and relevance
If we put cookies in place, you will be told about their use and the point of collecting data through cookies.
We obtain your consent
Before we place any cookies on your equipment, we will ask for your consent. However, cookies needed to guarantee functionality and settings can be used without your consent.
You can obtain more information about our policy on the use of cookies and how to delete or reject them here. If you wish to revoke your consent, please see the guidelines under our cookies policy.
YOUR RIGHTS
You are entitled to access your personal information
You are entitled at all times to be told what information about you we are processing, where it originates, and what we are using it for. You can also be told how long we store your personal information for and who receives information about you, as and when we disclose information.
If requested, we can tell you about the information we are processing about you. However, such access may be limited for the sake of protecting other people’s privacy, trade secrets and intellectual property rights.
You can take advantage of your rights by contacting us. You will find our contact details at the top.
You are entitled to have personal information corrected, deleted or blocked, or to demand restrictions on processing
You are entitled at any time to have incorrect personal information we are processing about you corrected. You must contact us and tell us the nature of such inaccuracies and how they can be rectified.
In some cases we will have an obligation to delete your personal information. This applies, for example, if you revoke your consent and we cannot process your information on any other basis. If you think your information is no longer necessary for the purpose for which we obtained it, you can also ask to have it deleted. You can also contact us if you feel that your personal information is being processed contrary to the legislation or other legal duties.
Furthermore, in some cases, you also have the right to have your personal information blocked or to demand restrictions on its processing.
If requested to correct, delete or restrict your personal information, or to restrict its processing, we will investigate whether the conditions have been met and, if so, carry out your request as quickly as possible.
You are entitled to object to our processing of your personal information
You are entitled to lodge an objection to our processing of your personal information.
You can use the contact details at the top to send an objection. If your objection is justified, we will arrange to have processing of your personal information discontinued.
You are entitled to receive your personal information in a commonly used format
In certain cases you are entitled to have the personal information we have registered about you provided in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and to ask us to transmit this information to another data controller.
AMENDMENT OF GUIDELINES
Fritz Hansen reserves the right to update and amend the guidelines in this policy. Whenever we do this, we will also correct the “most recently updated” date at the bottom of the document.
RIGHT OF COMPLAINT
If you wish to complain about the processing of your personal information, you can always contact us by e-mail or phone, as stated at the top. You can also apply to the Danish Data Protection Agency: Datatilsynet, Borgergade 28, 5., DK-1300 Copenhagen K, Denmark.
Last updated: 4 April 2019
